Arka Saha

860-781-1838 | arka.saha107@gmail.com | arka.saha@uconn.edu | LinkedIn | GitHub | Hartford, CT, USA

SUMMARY

Business/Data Analyst with **5+ years of progressive experience** in leading teams and delivering client-centric data solutions over 10+ projects across various domains. Experienced in data cleaning, pre-processing, wrangling, transformation, modelling using various predictive models and machine learning techniques, data forecasting, text mining and data visualization in tools such as Python and R

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut, Hartford, CT, USA

August 2021 – December 2022

Master of Science, Business Analytics and Project Management

Predictive Modelling, Statistics in Analytics, Data Management, Visual Analytics, Data Science with Python, Data mining & Forecasting

KIIT University, Bhubaneshwar, Odisha, India

May 2012 - August 2016

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Telecommunication

WORK EXPERIENCES

Capgemini Technology Services India Limited, Bangalore, India

November 2019 – August 2021

Business Analyst

- Analyzed, defined clients' business strategy, and determined system architecture requirements to achieve business goals and formulated strategic plans for development to sustain future project goals.
- Led a **team of 10 people** to successfully facilitate, operate, and support a highly sensitive migration project.
- Designed the ETL pipeline, improving the overall migration process time by 25% by configuring the databases and standardizing
 end to end project management workflow for better usage analysis & data migration.
- Devised and maintained 15+ relational database objects followed by tables, views, stored procedures & triggers using T-SQL.
- Assembled & queried data from multiple sources ~10M rows of data, performed EDA, data manipulation, data modeling, transformation, data analysis, and identified correlations & patterns to create data models.
- Improved resolution time by 20% by addressing & resolving 200+ service request/defect tickets on ServiceNow and Jira.
- Built predicted models on historical ServiceNow data of around 5 defects/service requests over the past 3 years to forecast future trends of incidents and recommended data driven insights to the business to improve the performance of the project
- Enhanced customer satisfaction by 15% by identifying critical performance issues and leveraging tools Power BI dashboards by including various metrics and KPIs to gauge progress, and insights to help identify future growth.

• Accenture Solutions Private Limited, Bangalore, India

May 2016 – November 2019

SAP Migration Consultant

- Consulted with the customers to get a big-picture idea of the company's data needs, and successfully implemented end to end solution using SAP Business Objects Data Services (ETL Tool) in an agile project.
- Created ad hoc reports, minimizing nearby 80% of the errors by comparing the past/historic records against current data.
- Developed end-to-end analysis of KPIs using SQL to identify bottlenecks and proposed data-driven solutions to improve data performance, reducing operational costs by 7% by minimizing in-person intervention, further reducing errors.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel VLOOKUP/XLOOKUP, pivot tables, and Tableau visualizations to uncover new sights and increase revenue
 by \$1.15 million by identifying and presenting indicators, trends, outliers, and patterns.
- Provided recommendations to the customer by cleaning and transforming data from multiple data warehouses, analyzing using SQL and Python to run data models & discovering insights about new and past-released policies.

OTHER EXPERIENCES – ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Restaurant Recommendation Restaurant Recommendation System (*Python*) Analyzed customer data using EDA and modeled a recommendation system, which suggests a restaurant to a user based on the user's current location, using predictive models and Machine Learning techniques in python *pandas, geopandas, folium, Scikit-learn, NumPy.*
- Credit Card Customer Churn Performed predictive analysis on credit card customer churn by building a predictive model (Linear/Multiple Regression, Neural Network, KNN, Decision Tree) with an accuracy of 91%, resulting in a decrease of churn by 35%.
- Weather Forecasting Designed a weather forecasting model to accurately forecast/predict the temperature, achieving an accuracy of 85% using various modeling techniques such as ARIMA, exponential smoothing and ARIMAX.
- Remote Working Survey Post Pandemic Created detailed & effective reports and dashboards to assess the productivity and morale
 implications of working remotely and outline an ideal policy for the future by extracting survey records from SQL and EXCEL, preprocessing and transforming using Power Query, modeling the data, formulating complex calculated columns & measures using DAX.

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Programming and Database: Python, R, C++, SAP HANA, T-SQL, Oracle SQL, MySQL, DynamoDB, VBA, DAX, M-Code, MS Access, Aurora
- Business Intelligence Tools: Power BI, Tableau, MS Excel, SSRS, SAS, Power Automate, Power Platform, GIT, Power Pivot
- Cloud Platforms AWS (EC2, CloudWatch, CloudFront, S3, Lambda, AWS Glue, VPC), Azure (Azure Machine Learning)
- ETL tools & Project Management: MS Project, Visio, SAP Business Objects Data Services, Informatica, HP ALM, Jira, Syniti DSP, SAP HANA
- ML Techniques Pandas, TensorFlow, SciKit-Learn, NumPy, Matplotlib, Regression, Classification, Clustering, NLP, Error Metrics
- Statistical Techniques Hypothesis & A/B Testing, Confidence & Predictive Intervals, t-test, chi-square, ANOVA, Correlation, Regression
- Certifications Microsoft Certified Data Analyst Associate, Tableau Desktop Specialist, DP 900, AWS CCP, Google Certified Data Analyst